Here, I'll step through the arm_mover code and explain what's going on.
在这里 我会全面接受 arm_mover 代码并解释发生了什么
The imported modules for arm_mover are the same as
导入的 arm_mover 模块与
simple_arm with the exception of two new imports.
Simple_arm 完全相同 除了两个新的导入
Namely, the joint state message and the simple Arm Service Module.
即 关节状态消息和简单机器臂服务模块
Joint state messages are published to the simple_arm/joint_states topic,
关节状态消息发布到 simple_arm/joint_states主题
and are used for monitoring the position of the arm.
并用于监测机器臂的位置
The simple arm package and the service module,
简单机器臂包和服务模块
SRV, are automatically generated by Catkin as part of the build process.
SRV 由 Catkin 自动生成 这是构建过程的一部分
The app goal function returns true if the joint positions are close to the goals.
如果联合位置接近目标 则应用目标函数返回 true
When taking measurements from sensors in the real world,
当从现实世界的传感器取测量值时
there'll always be some amount of noise.
总会有一些噪音
The same is true for joint positions reported by the gazebos simulator.
由 gazebos 模拟器报告的联合位置也是如此
If both positions are within 0.05 radians of the goal, true is returned.
如果两个位置都在目标的 0.05 弧度范围内 则返回 true
The clamp and boundaries function is responsible for
夹具和边界功能负责
enforcing the minimum and maximum joint angles for each joint.
执行每个关节的最小和最大关节角度
If the joint angles passed are outside of the operable range,
如果传递的关节角度在可操作范围之外
they'll be clamped to the nearest allowable value.
则会被限制在最接近的允许值
The minimum and maximum joint angles are retrieved from the parameter server,
每次夹具和边界被调用时
each time clamp and boundaries is called.
都会从参数服务器中检索最小和最大关节角度
The Tildy here is the private namespace qualifier,
这里的 Tildy 私有名称空间限定符
and indicates that the parameter which we wish to get is within the node's namespace.
它表明了希望得到的参数在节点的名称空间内
For example, here it's /simple_ arm/.
例如 这里是 /simple_arm/
The second parameter is the default value to be returned in the case
第二个参数是 Rospy.get_param 无法从参数服务器
that rospy.get_param was unable to get the parameter from the param server.
获取参数时 返回的默认值
The rest of this function simply clamps the joint angle if necessary.
如果需要 该函数的其余部分可以仅负责夹紧关节角度
Warning messages are logged if the requested joint angles are out of bounds.
如果请求的关节角度超出范围 则会记录警告消息
The move arm function commands the arm to move,
移动臂功能会命令机器臂移动
returning the amount of time that elapsed while the arm was moving.
并返回机器臂移动时所耗费的时间
Note. Within the function we are using the rospy.wait_for_message
注意： 在函数内我们使用 rospy.wait_for_message
call to receive joint_state messages from the /simple_arm/joint_states topic.
调用以接收来自 /simple_arm/joint_states 主题的 joint_state 消息
This is a blocking function call.
这是一个阻塞函数调用
Meaning that it will not return until a message has been
意思是说 在收到在简单机器臂/联合状态主题上消息之前
received on the simple arm/joint states topic.
它不会返回
In general, you should not use wait_for_message.
一般来说 你不应该使用 wait_for_message
We simply use it here for the sake of clarity and because move_arm is being called from
为了清晰起见 我们在这里地使用了它 因为 move_arm 被从
the handle_safe_move_request function which demands
Handle_safe_move_request 中函数调用
that the response message is passed back as a return parameter.
该函数要求 该响应消息作为返回参数传回
We'll talk more about this in a moment.
我们稍后再讨论这个问题
This is the service handler function.
这是服务句柄函数
When a service client sends
当服务客户端发送
a GoToPositionRequest to the safe_move service this function is called.
一个 GoToPositionRequest 到 safe_move 服务时 这个函数被调用
The function parameter REQ or request is a type
函数参数 REQ 或请求是
GoToPositionRequest the service response is a type GoToPositionResponse.
GoToPositionRequest 类型 服务响应是 GoToPositionResponse 类型
This service function handler is called whenever a new service request is received.
只要收到新的服务请求 就会调用此服务函数处理程序
The response to the service request is returned from the function.
从该函数返回对服务请求的响应
Another note here.
还有个地方需要注意
The move arm function is blocking and
移动手臂功能正在阻塞
will not return until the arm has finished its movement.
直到手臂完成移动才会返回
Incoming messages cannot be processed and no other useful work
可以在机器臂执行其移动命令时 传入的消息无法处理
can be done in the python script while the arm is performing its movement command.
也无法在python脚本中完成其他有效的工作
While this poses no real problem for
虽然这对本例而言并不构成真正的问题
this example it is a practice that should generally be avoided.
但通常应该避免这种做法
One great way to avoid blocking the threat of
一种避免执行阻塞发生的好方法是
execution would be to use an action rather than a service.
使用动作而不是服务
You can find some more information about when it's best to use
在下面的链接里 你可以找到关于何时最适合使用
a topic versus a service versus an action in the links below.
主题 何时使用服务的更多说明
Here the node is initialized with the name arm_mover
这里 节点是用名字 arm_mover 初始化的
and the GoToPositionService is created with the name safe_move.
并使用名称 safe_move 创建了 GoToPositionService
As mentioned previously the Tildy qualifier identifies
如前所述 Tildy 限定词表示
that safe_move is meant to belong to the nodes private namespace.
该 safe_move 应该属于节点私有名称空间
The resulting service name will be /arm_mover/safe_move.
生成的服务名称将为 /arm_mover/safe_move
The thirm parameter to the
Thirm 参数
rospy.service_call is the function
在 rospy.service_call 中是
that should be called when a service request is received.
收到服务请求时调用的功能
Lastly, rospy.spin simply blocks until the shutdown request is received by the node.
最后 rospy.spin 会保持阻塞 直到节点收到关闭请求为止
Failure to include this line would result in
如未能包括这一行 会导致
mover_service returning and the script completing execution.
Mover_service 返回 并且脚本完成执行
Finally, we have the if_name_=_main block.
最后 我们有 if_name _=_ main 这部分代码
This section of code is similar to that of simple_mover.
它与 simple_mover 类似